"Nuna"?
“Nunna”？
ALARM
（鬧鐘）
"Nuna…"
“Nunna”
What does that mean?
到底是什麼意思啊？
Good morning!
早安…
Good morning.
早安
Nuna… Nuna!
姐…
Huh?
什麼？
Nuna?
“Nunna”？
Look, my daughter's favorite scene is coming up.
你看，這是咱女兒最喜歡的一幕
Did she contact you?
她有和你聯絡嗎？
No, I found this on her social media.
沒有，我是透過她的社群帳號得知的
A father checking their daughter's social media is terrifying.
被父親追蹤帳號也未免太可怕了吧
I'm your big sister!
相信我！我是你姐呀！
There's no way you're my big sister!
你怎麼可能是我姐！
I'm not lying.
我沒騙你！
I'm your big sister.
我真的是你姐啦！
Your daughter enjoys this?
你女兒喜歡這種類型的？
You could say she's a genius.
她可以說是天才型哪
I'm your big sister.
我是你姐！
Are you really my big sister?
你真的是我姐？
Big Sis?
姐姐？
Yes, I'm your big sister!
對！我是姐姐！
Hey, doesn't this old guy look like you?
話說這大叔長得很像你對吧？
What if I were your nuna--
如果咱是仁科小姐的姐姐…
-I'd hate that. -Of course.
-我死都不要 -我想也是
I never stopped looking for you.
我也一直在找你
Me neither.
姐姐也是
Big Sis?
“姐姐”？
-Good morning.
-早安
Good morning.
早啊
The meeting will start in five minutes.
五分鐘之後要開會
Okay.
好的
It's thanks to all of you that we got through the Chocolat Festival.
感謝各位的努力 巧克力慶典才能圓滿落幕
-Thank you.
-各位辛苦了 -辛苦了
On the first day, we achieved our highest sales ever.
在活動首日，還創下了 公司開業以來最佳的銷售成績
Business was booming.
畢竟是盛況空前哪
Here are the results from the survey we conducted at the Chocolat Festival.
至於這個則是在巧克力慶典會場 收到的問卷統計結果
REASON FOR PURCHASE
（購買理由）
As of right now,
就現況來看
our taste and packaging have brought us plenty of fans.
我們在口味和包裝 兩方面都獲得足夠的支持
Now I'd finally like us to gain recognition for…
接下來我們要讓更多人認識的…
environmental friendliness.
就是“環保”這塊
It's 7%?
只有7%？
That's surprisingly low.
實際上沒什麼人知道呢
But our biggest selling point is that we use discarded cacao.
用廢棄可可做成商品 明明才是咱們最大的賣點
It'd be nice if more people knew.
真希望能推廣出去
this is our chance to highlight our work.
我認為現在正是 宣揚公司行動的好機會
So, in regards to our seminar next week,
所以關於下週要舉行的研討會
I'd like to revise the contents to fit our ideology more.
我打算將內容改得更符合我們的理念
And we have Tae-o, an environmental expert.
正好團隊裡有熟悉環保問題的泰晤
Yes.
好的
We reserved a venue at Tae-o's university so we can target students.
為了方便學生參加研討會 到時會由泰晤的大學提供場地
You'll be in charge, Tae-o. Is that okay?
這部分要交給泰晤負責，你可以嗎？
Yes, but if it's possible,
可以，不過我希望
it'd be nice to have something they can touch and taste.
到時能提供 讓大家實際觸摸和品嚐的食品
I see.
這樣啊
Maybe they can smell the cacao beans used for chocolate, or taste cacao nibs.
讓聽眾聞聞巧克力的原料 可可豆的香味
Nice idea.
不錯的主意耶
So, that's cacao beans and cacao nibs.
那我們需要可可豆、可可碎粒
And cacao husks, too. Aihara, get those ready.
還有可可豆殼，由相原準備好
Yes, leave it to me.
好的，請包在我身上
Nishina, please support Tae-o.
仁科小姐，麻煩你支援泰晤
Okay.
了解
I'll be in your care.
麻煩你了
-Ask me anything. -Okay.
-有問題儘管問喔 -好
Tae-o, just think of Nishina as your nuna.
泰晤，你可以把仁科小姐 當成你的“Nunna”喲
Nishina is your nuna, Tae-o.
仁科小姐就是泰晤的“Nunna”
Nuna.
Nunna
"Nuna"?
-“Nunna”？ -Nunna
You just wanted to show off what you learned earlier.
你只是想秀剛才學到的單字吧？
-What was that? -Nuna.
-什麼意思？ -Nunna
-It's fine, Tae-o.
-別在意，你不用聽他的
Yes, nuna.
就是“Nunna”
Nuna? Big Sis?
“Nunna”？“姐姐”？
BIG SISTER, NUNA
（姐姐、Nunna）
NUNA MEANS "BIG SISTER" IN KOREAN
（在韓語中 “Nunna”的意思是“姐姐”）
So it does mean big sister.
果然是“姐姐”
WHAT EXACTLY IS A NUNA?
（“Nunna”到底是什麼？）
You hear "nuna" all the time, but what does it even mean?
常常聽人家說“Nunna” 這到底是什麼意思？
Yeah. I'll do my best.
好，加油吧
Tae-o. Here.
泰晤，這給你
For me?
送我的？
To me, Yuri is…
這表示侑里小姐對我…
No, wait.
不，應該說在她心中 我是個特別的存在吧？
Yeah, Senpai?
你好，學長
I heard about the seminar.
我聽說你們要開研討會
The professor told me to help out since you're working so hard.
教授說你很努力，叫我幫你一把 有沒有什麼需要協助的？
Oh, in that case,
這樣啊，那樣的話
can you double-check my facts about the animals?
可以幫我檢查看看 動物那部分有沒有錯誤嗎？
Got it.
知道了
I have time after 3:30 p.m. on Monday.
我週一下午3點30分以後應該有空
Then I'll see you at the lab.
那麼我這就去研究室
Thank you.
謝謝學長
Sure.
不會
Oh, right.
對了
Take this as a thank you for today.
這個送你，謝謝你今天來一趟
It's linaria chocolate I made just for today, not meant for sale.
這是我特製的姬金魚草巧克力 是非賣品喔
Oh, the girl you like gave me chocolate. Thank her for me.
話說你喜歡的那個女生送過巧克力 幫我跟她道謝
Okay.
好的
Huh? What did you say?
不會吧？你說什麼？
The person I like?
我喜歡的人？
Then what is this?
那這代表什麼意思？
"Nuna" means big sister.
“Nunna”的意思是“姐”
In Korea, the word nuna
韓國人說“Nunna”
refers to your biological sister or an older woman who you're close with.
是用來稱呼親姐姐 或是關係親近的年長女性
"Who you're close with"…
“關係親近”
Idols often use this with older female fans.
偶像也常常這樣 稱呼年長的女粉絲喔
-Like, "Nuna, thanks for the letters! -Fans?
-比方說像“謝謝姐姐們！” -粉絲？
A lot of Japanese women feel their heart skip a beat when they're called nuna.
應該有很多日本女生 聽到人家叫你“Nunna”會心動
But they actually use nuna a lot even when you're not a romantic interest.
不過就算對方不是戀愛對象
So don't let it get your hopes up, everyone.
所以大家不要想太多喔
Cute.
真可愛
I like that side of you.
我就喜歡你這一點
Please go on a date with me.
請跟我約會
You're as pretty as always today.
你今天一樣可愛
But I want to be someone special to you.
我好想成為你心中特別的人啊
He doesn't see me
原來他…
as a romantic interest?
沒有把我視作戀愛對象？
-We're back. -Hey there.
-我們回來了 -辛苦了
Good work today. Have you eaten?
辛苦了，各位吃過飯了嗎？
He's asking them too.
他又在問了
Tae-o, you always care so much about if people ate.
泰晤，總覺得你好像 老是在問別人有沒有吃飯耶
We haven't. Should we finally go today?
還沒吃哪，今天要一起去吃嗎？
My newest recommendations are avant-garde tonkotsu ramen or neo-Korean food.
咱最近推薦進化型豚骨拉麵 還有新韓式料理
Oh, avant-garde tonkotsu ramen is fine too.
吃進化型豚骨拉麵也不錯喲
If you want tonkotsu ramen, just say it.
你想吃豚骨拉麵就直說啦
Yuri, did you eat?
侑里小姐，吃早餐了嗎？
Have you eaten?
你吃飯了嗎？
Let's eat.
一起吃飯吧
HAVE YOU EATEN? KOREA
（吃過飯了嗎？韓國）
Tonkotsu ramen would've been nice.
咱比較想吃豚骨拉麵
We already decided on Korean food.
不是已經決定吃韓式料理了嗎？
When Korean people say, "Have you eaten?",
韓國人問“吃過飯了嗎？”
it's the same as when a Japanese person says, "Hello, how are you?"
就等於日本人問“最近好嗎？” 跟“過得好嗎？”
Yet when a Korean guy asks a Japanese person that,
可是日本女生聽到韓國男生問 “吃過飯了嗎？”的反應都是
they might think, "What? Could they be inviting me?"
“什麼？是要約我出去嗎？” 大家可能會這麼覺得啦
But it doesn't mean they're inviting you to a meal.
但對方其實沒有要約你吃飯的意思
-So, don't get the wrong idea. -Really?
-千萬不要誤會喔 -原來是這樣啊？
My Japanese friends often ask,
我有一個日本朋友
"Hey, Kibarun, my Korean friend asked me if I've eaten--"
一直說她常被韓國人問吃飽沒…
HOW DO YOU USE "JOA" PROPERLY?
（“Joa”正確的用法是？）
How do you even use "joa"properly?
“Joa”這句話 到底該怎麼正確使用？
Korean, just like English, has two words when expressing attraction.
韓語跟英語很像
Joa is "like" in English.
“Joa”就像英文的“喜歡”
Saranghae is "love."
“Saranghae”才是“愛”
And when the word "joa"--
然後“Joa”是“喜歡”的意思…
He hasn't said "saranghae" to me.
他沒對我說過“Saranghae”
Actually, in Korea, when you express your love to a romantic interest,
韓國人在對心上人表達愛意的時候
they often use "saranghae" instead of "joa."
比起“Joa”，更常講“Saranghae”
So, Koreans will often chant
所以韓國粉絲對喜歡的偶像
"saranghae," which means "I love you," to their favorite idols instead of "joa."
表現“我愛你”時不會說“Joa” 而是一直喊“Saranghae”
So, just because you were told "joa hae"--
因此大家聽到 有人對你說“Joa hae”…
Oh, sorry.
哦，抱歉
I knocked.
我剛剛有敲門
Right, okay.
是喔，好
It's about Tae-o.
我想討論泰晤的事情
Huh?
什麼？
His internship period is ending soon.
他的實習期間就快結束了
I want to decide within the month if we'll hire him.
我想在這個月內先決定好 之後要不要正式錄用他
Oh.
哦
I see. Right.
對喔，說得也是
If tomorrow's seminar goes well,
如果明天的研討會順利成功
I'm thinking of hiring him.
我就打算錄用他
How about you?
你覺得呢？
And what does he want?
他本人的意願呢？
He wants to join us.
他也希望被我們正式錄用
I see.
這樣啊
Then let's move forward with that.
那此事就照那方向處理吧
How about you?
本宮有何想法？
Is that okay, Motomiya?
本宮，你能接受？
You're not like yourself lately, Motomiya.
你最近有些不尋常
You're not influenced by emotion.
你這個人不會輕易受感情影響
That's why I trust you.
正因為你為人如此 我才會對你深信不疑
-And the company-- -I know.
-公司… -我知道
I know that better than anyone.
我自己最清楚
Of course,
關於…
I want you to decide whether to hire Tae-o or not
要不要正式錄用泰晤
after seeing how capable he is.
當然得看他本人的能力再決定
Got it.
明白了
Fried and yangnyeom chicken. Enjoy.
這是炸物與韓式辣醬炸雞，請慢用
Thank you.
謝謝
Listen here, Tae-o.
聽好了，泰晤
Apparently, the boss has been longing for this seminar since founding the company.
這場研討會聽說是 社長創業以來的夙願喔
"Longing"? What does that mean?
“夙願”？什麼意思？
It means she has wanted this for a long time.
就是一直很想實現的願望
Really?
真的嗎？
Company ideologies like ours tend to be seen as overly conscious.
像咱們這種企業的理念 容易被人嘲笑說是誇大其詞
First, we focus on the chocolate's taste and build up our name.
社長一直說要堅持巧克力的美味 先打響知名度
Then, one day, we'll share our ideology. That's what she always said.
然後在未來希望顧客們 也知道公司的理念
Really?
原來是這樣啊？
That's true.
也對
Now that the company has grown a bit,
現在公司已經成長到一定的規模
people might be inclined to hear us out.
可能就會有更多人願意傾聽了
Yeah, Hanaoka has been waiting for this chance.
沒錯，花岡就是在等這一刻到來
Why are you suddenly talking about Hanaoka?
為什麼會提到花岡先生？
Hanaoka's raison d'être is to make our boss's dream come true.
因為實現社長的夢想 就是花岡他的人生目標啊
What do you mean?
那是什麼意思？
Yeah, he does give off that vibe.
對耶，好像是有那種感覺
I see it.
你那樣講沒錯呢
Yeah, their bond is unbreakable.
他們兩人有很深的羈絆哪
True. I've never seen the boss rely on anyone besides Hanaoka.
說來也對，我沒看過社長 依賴花岡先生以外的人
To the boss, Hanaoka is special--
畢竟對社長來說 花岡先生是個特別的…
Special?
特別？
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
Oh, no.
不行
-Are you okay? -What's wrong?
-你還好嗎？ -怎麼了？
-Take a seat. -I'll…
-坐下吧 -我…
head back first.
先回去了
-Huh? -We're still…
-什麼？ -還剩很多耶…
-You're not done eating. -Tae-o.
-飯還沒吃完耶 -泰晤
-Huh? -I'm taking your japchae.
-怎麼了？ -雜菜咱吃掉囉
What?
幹嘛啦？
Why?
為什麼？
Motomiya's out.
本宮她外出了
I see.
這樣啊
Are you special, Hanaoka?
花岡先生是特別的嗎？
What?
什麼？
Am I not special?
我不是特別的存在嗎？
It's time. I'm heading to the university.
時間差不多了，我要去大學了
What?
你說什麼？
I'm buying a watch. Just you wait.
我一定要買支錶！
This is the seminar venue.
這裡就是研討會會場
When you're done, please tell the office.
結束之後請告知事務人員
-Thank you.
-謝謝你 -謝謝
Sorry I made you visit with me when you're dealing with love troubles.
不好意思，你為了感情如此傷腦筋 還讓你陪我來勘查會場
No, not at all.
不用介意
Looks like we'll have plenty of space for taste testing.
這樣看來有足夠空間可以試吃 應該也不需要廚房
Really? That's great.
是喔，那就好
Um, love guru.
請問一下，老師
Yes, please share what happened with me.
好，跟老師坦承發生了什麼事吧
Let's take a seat and collect ourselves.
坐吧，總之先坐下來冷靜一下
Hello.
你好
Oh, Tae-o.
哦，泰晤
Wait one second.
等一下喔
Tae-o.
泰晤
Professor, thank you for the seminar venue.
老師，謝謝你幫我借研討會會場
Oh, it's fine. Anything for you.
不客氣，因為是泰晤的要求嘛
It's also my duty to show students
而且讓學生們知道他們還能選擇 在那樣的企業中一展長才
Thank you.
謝謝
More importantly, Tae-o,
話說回來啊，泰晤
how are things going with the person you like?
你和心上人發展得怎麼樣了？
I'm not special.
我不是她特別的人
What? Not a romantic interest?
什麼？不是戀愛對象？
Not special?
不特別？
Nuna, huh?
“Nunna”呀？
In what context did he call you that?
他是在什麼狀況下這麼叫你的？
He didn't call me that directly.
他其實沒有直接這樣叫我
He said it indirectly?
那是間接叫你？
Why don't you ask him then?
那你去問他不就好了嗎？
Ask what?
問什麼？
What does "nuna" mean?
“Nunna是什麼？
Am I not a romantic interest?
我不是戀愛對象嗎？
Didn't you want to eat with me?
你不是想跟我一起吃飯嗎？
Don't you love me?
難道你不愛我嗎？”
Do you really think I can ask that?
你覺得我問得出口嗎？
But, wait.
而且等一下
Do you want to date him?
侑里小姐，你想和他交往嗎？
What do you mean you're not special?
你說不是她特別的人 這是什麼意思？
No, Tae-o, I think that's just a misunderstanding.
不，我覺得你是誤會了，泰晤
Then what's that?
那這盒又是怎麼回事？
What is that?
這是什麼東西？
I got it from the person Tae-o likes.
這是泰晤喜歡的人送我的
I see.
是喔
What?!
搞什麼？
Onoda, how could you do that?!
小野田，你這個人怎麼如此差勁啊？
I've misjudged you!
我真是看錯你了！
It was a thank-you gift.
我這盒是人情巧克力啦
Tae-o's was the real deal.
泰晤那盒才是真愛巧克力
No.
不
It's the same chocolate.
是同一款巧克力
-Cute.
-真可愛
Mine is not romantic either.
我的也是人情巧克力
No, you've got it all wrong.
不，不是那樣的
How do I put this?
該怎麼說才好呢？
Notice her love.
你要明白她的心意啊
I think…
我的心意…
She has noticed my feelings.
她應該是明白的
But…
可是…
She has another special someone.
對她來說有另一個特別的人
Dating…
關於想不想交往…
I'm not really sure about that.
我還不太確定
And if we hire him, I'll officially be his boss and he'll be my employee.
而且要是正式錄用了他 我們就是真正的上司和下屬
On top of all that, I'm his nuna.
但最大的問題是 對他來說，我只是個大姐姐
Those are all excuses.
找了一堆藉口呢
I mean, I'm scared.
因為我會怕
Of what?
怕什麼呢？
I'm scared…
我怕泰晤…
of learning that Tae-o…
其實不喜歡我
doesn't like me.
我害怕得知這真相
I wonder…
她或許…
if she won't fall in love with me.
不可能再喜歡我了
I'm telling you--
你聽我說…
Hanaoka is special.
花岡先生才是特別的
I wonder if she likes Hanaoka.
她是不是喜歡花岡先生呢？
It's not like that.
就跟你說不是了
You're being loud!
很吵耶！
My apologies!
抱歉！
Well, I don't know if I'm allowed to tell you,
好啦，我是不知道該不該說
but I'll say it since I shouldn't have to keep it a secret.
不過我一個人藏在心裡 好像也不太對，我就直說了
The person you like asked for my advice.
泰晤喜歡的那個女生來找我商量過
That chocolate was just her way of thanking me.
這盒巧克力只是她的謝禮
Advice?
商量？
She said you made her heart pound.
她還說只要一想到你就會心悸
Pound?
心悸？
Don't you get it?
你應該懂吧？
Her heart fluttered.
就是心臟怦怦跳啊
Fluttered?
怦怦跳？
Notice her love already.
你要察覺她的愛意啊
Yuri, do you know the essential "-ing" for romance?
侑里小姐，你知道戀愛需要的 “ING”是什麼嗎？
I've heard of it before.
我好像聽說過
Wasn't it timing, feeling, and happening?
我記得是 “時機、感覺、意外”對吧？
No, it's not three things. It's just one.
不對喔，沒有三個那麼多，只有一個
What is it?
是什麼？
Fighting!
是“Fighting”
You have to fight.
你要勇敢“奮鬥”啊
I have to fight?
要我奮鬥？
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Romance is impossible if you're too afraid to know how he feels.
若你害怕知道對方的內心想法 是沒辦法談戀愛的
You need to be prepared to fight.
你要做好奮鬥的覺悟才行
The doctor.
是博士
Why is he here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
Tae-o was just here too.
泰晤他剛剛也在這裡喔
He wanted to see the coral tank first, so he might still be here.
他說要看看珊瑚的水槽再回去 我想他應該還在校內
Where is that tank?
你說的水槽在哪裡？
It's near the cafeteria.
在咖啡廳附近
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Good luck!
奮鬥吧！
Are you sure?
這樣好嗎？
Of course. This is incredible growth for her.
不只好，還是一次飛躍性的成長啊
But why's the CEO going?
可是為什麼是社長過去？
Shouldn't you be going?
這時應該是你去追吧？
What?
為什麼啊？
Anyway, why are you here?
比起這件事，你為什麼會在這裡？
Returning library books.
我是來還書的
But aren't you a doctor?
你不是醫生嗎？
A doctor? Well, I am from the department of veterinary science.
醫生？也算吧 我是獸醫系畢業的沒錯
Oh, you're a veterinarian?
是喔，所以你是獸醫？
I'm not.
不是
Huh? What's going on?
什麼？怎麼回事？
What are you?
你到底是什麼人啊？
Tae-o…
泰晤
Tae-o?!
泰晤？
What?
什麼？
Oh, if you're looking for Tae-o, he already left.
哦，是要找泰晤的話 他已經回去了喔
Oh, is that so?
是喔，原來是這樣
Excuse me.
不好意思
He wasn't here.
他明明就不在嘛
By doctor, he meant he's in academics, not medicine?
原來說你是“Doctor” 不是指“醫生”，而是“博士”
Are you for real?
搞什麼嘛！
Well, I don't care.
算了，怎樣都無所謂
You're a man of my past anyway.
反正我對你已經沒感覺了
What?
什麼？
By the way, why didn't you become a vet?
話說回來，你為什麼不當獸醫？
I couldn't. I'm not good with blood.
我當不了，我怕看到血
That's rough.
太致命了
Here we go. Huh? Hm?
看我的，拿不到耶，什麼？
Although I do occasionally run into blood in the lab.
不過我在研究的時候 也很常看見血就是了
You're hopeless.
那根本就不行嘛
I've gotten over it.
不過我已經克服了
Everything happens for a reason.
一切事物都有原因
I think it's because I realized
只要知道流血的原因
it's not that scary if I know why blood comes out.
就會發現這其實沒有什麼好怕的
Maybe you could've become a vet.
那你不就可以當獸醫了嗎？
True.
說得也是
But even if I became a vet,
不過我就算當上了獸醫
I'd probably have done research instead of clinical work.
比起做臨床，應該還是會選擇做研究
Why?
為什麼？
Because I like it.
因為我喜歡
Then, by chance…
那我想確認…
do you also want to know why I invited you out
我在情人節那天 約小野田先生出來的原因
on Valentine's Day?
你會不會想知道？
There's no mistaking it.
絕對不會錯
She wants love advice from you,
她是來找你做戀愛諮詢的
as she surely must like Tae-o as well.
她鐵定也喜歡泰晤
I already know why.
我已經知道是為什麼了
You do?
你知道了？
Yes, and I'm giving it a lot of thought.
我不只知道，也對此想了很多
You can trust me.
我不會辜負你的
Then is it okay if I keep my hopes up?
既然如此
Yes, please. Keep your hopes up.
請你好好期待吧
It's gotten romantic now, hasn't it?
氣氛浪漫起來了，對吧？
TAE-O LET'S GO AGAIN. GOOD NIGHT.
（泰晤 下次再一起去吧！晚安）
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO? DID YOU GO HOME ALREADY?
（你在做什麼？回家了嗎？）
I want to see him.
我好想見他
Well, tomorrow's the seminar.
不過明天還有研討會
TAE-O HAS SENT A MESSAGE
（泰晤傳來訊息）
Everything's set for tomorrow.
明天的準備都做好了！
LEAVE IT TO ME
（包在我身上）
Yuri, is something up?
侑里小姐，怎麼了嗎？
Are you ready for tomorrow?
明天沒問題嗎？
Oh, yes, it'll be fine.
哦，不要緊，沒問題的
I see.
這樣啊
Yes.
是的
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Hm?
什麼？
I'm by the swings.
我在鞦韆那邊
At the park?
你是說那座公園？
Yes.
對
Swinging sounds nice.
鞦韆感覺挺好玩的呢
Right now?
現在嗎？
Right now…
現在…
Or any other time.
是不用急啦
Is that so?
這樣啊
Then is it okay if I come over right now?
那我可以現在去嗎？
Right now…
現在來…
is fine too.
也是可以
Shall we meet?
要見個面嗎？
Yes.
好
KOTARO AIHARA HAS SENT A MESSAGE
（相原虎太郎傳來訊息）
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Yuri.
侑里小姐
I'm sorry.
對不起喔
About what?
為何要道歉？
It feels like I made you come here.
像是我硬是把你叫過來
It sounded like you wanted to see me.
因為我看你好像很想見我
I'm kidding.
開玩笑的，是我想見你
Shall we take a walk?
要一起散步嗎？
Yes.
好啊
-Um…
-那個…
Sorry, what is it?
抱歉喔，什麼事？
Sorry, what were you saying?
對不起，你剛才要說什麼？
Oh, it's nothing.
不，沒事
Let's climb up.
我們爬上去吧
Wait for me.
等我一下
You're slow.
你好慢喔
Your legs are longer than mine.
我們的腿長又不一樣
It's because you're small.
因為侑里小姐太矮了啊
I'm not small. I'm a normal size.
我不矮，是普通的平均身高
Oh, you're not small?
不矮嗎？
See, I'm not small.
你看，我不矮啊
How cute.
真可愛
What kind of advice did you want from Senpai?
你找學長商量了什麼事？
What?
什麼？
Is your heart fluttering?
會覺得心在怦怦跳嗎？
Yes.
會
Mine has been for a while too.
我也是，一直在跳
Why?
為什麼？
Why are you saying that?
為何要對我這麼說？
You don't know why?
你真的不曉得嗎？
I don't.
我不曉得
Do you know now?
現在明白了嗎？
I love you.
我愛你
Me too.
我也是
Hm?
嗯？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Yuri?
侑里小姐？
BUSINESSES CAN SOLVE ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES?!
（商業可以解決環境問題？）
WAITING ROOM
（等候室）
A medical doctor sounds nice,
雖然“醫生”的“Doctor”很棒
but a PhD sounds nice too.
不過當“博士”的“Doctor” 好像也不錯呢
-Yeah. -I've made up my mind.
-是喔 -我決定了
I'll make him fall for me after all.
我一定要攻陷他
Yeah.
是喔
He's a bit unique. A bit mysterious.
雖然他有點獨特，帶點神祕感
He's hard to figure out.
有點無法捉摸
He's also cryptic and can't take a hint,
總是講些莫名其妙的話 而且反應又遲鈍
but it's just enough for me to feel attracted.
可是就是那樣才讓人更起勁
Yeah.
是喔
I can get any man I want if I get serious.
只要我認真，沒有男人不會愛上我的
How about you? Did you two meet up?
侑里小姐，你後來有碰到他嗎？
What?
什麼？
Yeah, but…
有啊，可是…
I love you.
我愛你
I just had so much on my mind yesterday.
昨天我的思緒一團亂
But once this is over,
不過等這次研討會結束
I want to properly tell him how I feel.
我打算好好傳達自己的心意
Yes, I'm so proud of you!
很好，了不起！
Now that that's decided, let's get this seminar over with.
既然這麼決定了 就快把研討會辦完吧
What are you two doing?
你們在做什麼呀？
Could it be you're going after a student?
難不成是看上學生了？
In a sense, I guess he is a student.
他也算是學生沒錯啦
By the way, where are the cacao beans for tasting?
對了，相原，試吃用的可可豆呢？
I thought you were bringing them, Boss.
什麼？社長應該有帶來啊
What?
-什麼？ -怪了，我昨天有傳訊息過去吧？
A text?
訊息？
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Hello! I left the beans, nibs, and husks on your desk for tomorrow's seminar.
辛苦了！
Please take one last look.
麻煩社長做最終確認
I thought you'd check and bring them.
我以為社長確認完了會直接帶過來
You should've taken responsibility and brought them!
-不對吧，你要負責帶過來啊 -什麼？
I'm sorry, I'll go get them.
不好意思，我這就回去拿
But we're starting in ten minutes.
等等，再過十分鐘就要開始了
Sorry, I should've checked.
對不起，是我疏於確認
What do we do?
這下怎麼辦？
Okay, let's head over now.
好，我們差不多該進場了
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
I forgot the cacao husk samples at the office because of my oversight.
我一時沒有檢查到 將試吃用的可可豆殼忘在公司了
What do we do?
-該怎麼辦？ -你先冷靜
It's nothing to panic over.
不用如此著急
We can get cacao beans at the nearby import goods shop.
如果只要可可豆的話 應該可以在附近的進口超市買到
I'll go buy them.
-我這就去買！ -不，市售品的香氣不夠
Should we go without the beans?
還是乾脆不用可可豆？
Let's roast them.
不如烘焙吧
We'll roast them on the venue and have them smell the aroma.
我們改成現場烘焙可可豆 直接給學生們聞香氣
But we don't have a roaster.
可是我們沒有烘焙機啊
If it's just the aroma, we can use a frying pan instead.
如果只是要烘出香氣 可以改用平底鍋
There's a frying pan in the lab.
研究室裡有平底鍋
I'll borrow one from the doctor.
我這就去跟“Doctor”借
What? A doctor?
什麼？跟醫生借？
Aihara, go get beans from the shop.
相原，你負責去超市買可可豆回來
Got it.
好的
Sorry, can you guys set up? I'll see if we can use a fire in the room.
抱歉，可以麻煩你們準備嗎？
-Okay.
-好的
Hanaoka.
花岡
Sorry, I should've checked properly.
對不起，都怪我沒有好好確認
-You usually wouldn't make this error. -Okay then.
-這不像你平常會犯的錯 -好
Let's focus on work for now.
總之現在該專心在工作上
We'll figure it out.
不用擔心，我們會想辦法的
-Okay, then.
-好，就這樣
MASS PRODUCTION &amp; ANIMALS
（大量生產與瀕危動物的增加）
Here's a question for you all.
我要給各位出個問題
Do you know how many species on this planet as of now
大家知道在一年之內地球上
are facing extinction?
有多少種動物瀕臨滅絕嗎？
Yes.
我要回答
Is it about ten species?
大約十種嗎？
The answer is
正確答案是…
forty thousand species.
四萬種
There are many reasons as to why,
雖然有很多原因
but first, we can say that global warming is one of them.
但其中最主要的就是地球暖化
The smell of chocolate changes with roasting duration and temperature.
巧克力的香氣會隨著 烘焙的時間和溫度改變
For example, this is a light roast at a low temperature,
像我手上這些是用低溫淺焙的
so it causes a fruity, floral aroma.
就會帶有鮮明的花果香氣
Is that girl the one who Tae-o likes?
她就是泰晤的心上人嗎？
Bravo!
好極了！
Everyone, come to the front
請各位同學到台前來
and give it a smell.
親自聞聞看
People in the back too.
也請後面的學生過來
Come forward.
請來前面
Looks like things will be okay.
照這樣子來看，應該是沒問題
Yes.
是啊
It's all thanks to you, Hanaoka.
這都是你的功勞
As for Tae-o…
我們就讓泰晤…
Let's hire him.
正式被錄用吧
Yeah.
好
-Are you leaving? -Yeah.
-要回去了嗎？ -是啊
About today…
今天…
Thank you so much.
真的很謝謝你
Sorry, as always.
抱歉啊，每次都給你添麻煩
It's my job.
那就是我的職責所在
Good work.
辛苦了
Good work today.
辛苦你了
Also…
另外啊…
Let me make this clear.
我先說一聲
There's no rule against dating co-workers.
公司並未明令禁止辦公室戀情
What?
什麼？
No, I--
-不，我… -任誰都看得出來
I'm fine now.
我的心情怎樣都好
This is fine.
這樣就好
I'm okay with this.
這樣就夠了
What?
什麼？
Anyway,
總之啊
that's all.
我只是想跟你說一聲罷了
I've always loved you.
我從很久以前就喜歡你了
See you tomorrow.
明天見囉
I thought I'd never again
我一直以為自己
be oblivious to someone's feelings.
不可能會摸不清別人內心的想法
But maybe it's precisely because I can read people's thoughts
不過有時可能就是因為會讀心
that I never tried to notice people's true feelings.
才讓我一直以來都沒嘗試過 去深入了解別人的真心話
I've always loved you.
我從很久以前就喜歡你了
Even when it came to someone precious who was always close by,
就連陪伴在我身邊 我極為珍視之人的心情也是
I was oblivious this entire time.
我一直都不知道
Yuri.
侑里小姐
I…
我…
want to be someone special to you.
想成為侑里小姐心中特別的人
Hm?
什麼？
How do you feel about Hanaoka?
侑里小姐，你對花岡先生 有怎樣的感覺？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Is Hanaoka someone special to you?
花岡先生是特別的嗎？
Do you like him?
你喜歡他嗎？
Why are you always running away?
為什麼你總是要逃避呢？
I…
我…
like you, Yuri.
喜歡侑里小姐
What about you, Yuri?
侑里小姐，你呢？
Do you not like me?
你不喜歡我？
I don't.
對
I'm sorry.
對不起
Subtitle translation by: Chul Woong Kim
字幕翻譯：江俊諺
It's like hell.
像是身處地獄
What is this?
這是怎樣？
Do you like Yuri?
你喜歡侑里小姐嗎？
Tae-o said he's not going home today.
泰晤說他今天不會回家
Please stop messing with me.
請你不要再戲弄我了
I haven't gotten to say how I feel.
我還沒有表達出自己的心意！